Welcome to this course on ChatGPT Prompt Engineering for Developers.
欢迎学习这门《面向开发者的ChatGPT提示工程》课程。
I'm thrilled to have with me, Isa Fulford, to teach this along with me.
我很高兴能邀请到Isa Fulford和我一起来教授这门课。
She is a member of the technical staff of OpenAI and had built the popular ChatGPT retrieval plugin
她是OpenAI技术团队的一员，之前开发了备受欢迎的ChatGPT检索插件。
and a large part of her work has been teaching people how to use LLM or large language model technology in products.
她的工作很大一部分是教人们如何在产品中使用LLM或大型语言模型技术。
She's also contributed to the OpenAI cookbook that teaches people prompting.
她还为OpenAI手册做出了贡献，指导人们如何进行提示。
So thrilled to have you with you.
非常高兴和你一起来授课。
And I'm thrilled to be here and share some prompting best practices with you all.
我也很高兴来到这里，和大家分享一些提示工程的最佳实践。
So there's been a lot of material on the Internet for prompting with articles like 30 prompts everyone has to know.
互联网上有很多关于提示工程的资料，比如“每个人都必须了解的30个提示”。
A lot of that has been focused on the ChatGPT web user interface, which many people are using to do specific and often one-off tasks.
很多内容都集中在ChatGPT的Web界面上，许多人用它来完成特定的、通常是一次性的任务。
But I think the power of LLM's large language models as a developer too,
但我认为，对于开发者而言，LLM大型语言模型的强大力量在于
that is using API calls to LLMs to quickly build software applications,
使用API调用大语言模型来快速构建软件应用的能力。
I think that is still very underappreciated.
我认为这一点仍然被严重低估。
In fact, my team at AIFund, which is a sister company to Deep Learning.AI,
实际上，我的团队在AI Fund工作，这是Deep Learning.AI的一个姐妹公司，
has been working with many startups on applying these technologies to many different applications.
一直在与许多初创公司合作，将这些技术应用到许多不同的应用场景。
And it's been exciting to see what LLM APIs can enable developers to very quickly build.
看到LLM API能让开发者迅速构建的成果令人非常兴奋。
So in this course, we'll share with you some of the possibilities
所以，在这门课程中，我们将与你分享一些可能性，
for what you can do as well as best practices for how you can do them.
你能做什么以及你如何实现它们的最佳实践。
There's a lot of material to cover.
内容很多啊
First, you'll learn some prompting best practices for software development.
首先，你将学习一些用于软件开发的提示的最佳实践。
Then we'll cover some common use cases, summarizing, inferring, transforming, expanding,
接下来我们将介绍一些常见的用例，如总结、推断、转换、扩展，
and then you'll build a chatbot using an LLM.
然后你将使用LLM构建一个聊天机器人。
We hope that this will spark your imagination about new applications that you can build.
我们希望这将激发你，关于可以构建新应用程序的想象力。
So in the development of large language models or LLMs,
因此，在大型语言模型或LLM的开发过程中，
there have been broadly two types of LLMs, which I'm going to refer to as base LLMs and instruction-tuned LLMs.
大致上有两种类型的LLM，我将它们称为基础型LLM和指令调整型LLM。
So base LLM has been trained to predict the next word based on text training data,
基础型LLM经过训练，可以根据文本训练数据预测下一个单词，
often trained on a large amount of data from the internet and other sources
通常在来自互联网和其他来源的大量数据上进行训练
to figure out what's the next most likely word to follow.
用来找出接下来最可能出现的单词。
So for example, if you were to prompt this, once upon a time there was a unicorn,
例如，如果你提示是，“从前有一个独角兽”，
it may complete this, that is, it may predict the next several words are
它可能会这样来完成回答，也就是说，它可能会预测接下来的几个单词是：
that live in a magical forest with all unicorn friends.
“和所有独角兽朋友一起生活在一个神奇的森林里”。
But if you were to prompt this with what is the capital of France,
但是，如果你用“法国的首都是什么？”来提问，
then based on what articles on the internet might have,
那么根据互联网上的文章可能有的内容，
it's quite possible that the base LLM will complete this with
基础型LLM很可能会这样完成这个问题，比如：
what is France's largest city, what is France's population, and so on,
（它会回答）法国最大的城市是什么、法国的人口是多少等等，
because articles on the internet could quite plausibly be lists of
因为互联网上的文章可能就是关于
quiz questions about the country of France.
法国这个国家的一系列问题。
In contrast, an instruction-tuned LLM, which is where a lot of momentum of LLM research and practice has been going,
相反，指令调整型LLM是LLM研究和实践的发展方向，
an instruction-tuned LLM has been trained to follow instructions.
指令调整型LLM已经被训练来遵循指令。
So if you were to ask it, what is the capital of France,
所以如果你问它，“法国的首都是什么？”，
it's much more likely to output something like the capital of France is Paris.
它更有可能输出类似于“法国的首都是巴黎”这样的答案。
The way that instruction-tuned LLMs are typically trained is
指令调整型LLM通常的训练方法是，
you start off with a base LLM that's been trained on a huge amount of text data
你首先从一个已经通过大量文本数据进行训练过的基础型LLM上开始，
and further train it, further fine-tune it with inputs and outputs that are instructions and good attempts to follow those instructions,
并通过输入和输出对其进行进一步训练，进一步微调，
that are instructions and good attempts to follow those instructions,
这些输入和输出都是指令以及遵循那些指令的良好尝试
and then often further refine using a technique called RLHF,
然后通常会使用一种叫做RLHF的技术进一步优化，
reinforcement learning from human feedback,
RLHF代表“从人类反馈中进行强化学习”，
to make the system better able to be helpful and follow instructions.
使系统更能提供帮助并遵循指令。
Because instruction-tuned LLMs have been trained
因为指令调整型LLMs已经被训练得
to be helpful, honest, and harmless,
更有益、诚实和无害，
so for example, they're less likely to output problematic text, such as toxic outputs, compared to base LLM,
举例来说，与基础型LLM相比，它们输出问题文本（如有毒输出）的可能性较小，
a lot of the practical usage scenarios have been shifting toward instruction-tuned LLMs.
许多实际使用场景已经转向了指令调整型LLMs。
Some of the best practices you find on the internet may be more suited for a base LLM,
你在互联网上找到的一些最佳实践可能更适合基础型LLM，
but for most practical applications today,
但对于如今大多数实际应用，
we would recommend most people instead focus on instruction-tuned LLMs,
我们建议大多数人转而关注经过指导微调的LLMs，
which are easier to use and also,
这些LLM更易于使用
because of the work of OpenAI and other LLM companies, becoming safer and more aligned.
因为OpenAI和其他LLM公司的努力，LLM变得越来越安全、一致。
So this course will focus on best practices for instruction-tuned LLMs,
所以本课程将关注指令调整型LLMs的最佳实践，
which is what we recommend you use for most of your applications.
这也是我们建议你在大多数应用中使用指令调整型LLMs的原因。
Before moving on, I just want to acknowledge the team from OpenAI
在继续后面内容之前，我想借此感谢OpenAI团队
and DeepLearning.ai that had contributed to the materials
以及DeepLearning.ai为这些教材做出贡献的人员
that Isa and I will be presenting.
也就是我和Isa即将展示的这些课程材料。
I'm very grateful to Andrew Mayne、Joe Palermo、Boris Power，
我非常感激来自OpenAI的Andrew Mayne、Joe Palermo、Boris Power，
Ted Sanders， and Lilian Weng from OpenAI that were very involved with us
Ted Sanders和Lilian Weng，他们积极与我们合作
brainstorming materials, vetting the materials to put together
一起头脑风暴讨论教材、审核教材，
the curriculum for this short course.
为这门短期课程制定课程大纲。
And I'm also grateful on the DeepLearning side for the work
同时我也感谢DeepLearning方面的工作，
of Geoff Ladwig, Eddy Shyu, and Tommy Nelson.
包括Geoff Ladwig、Eddy Shyu和Tommy Nelson的贡献。
So when you use an instruction-tuned LLM, think of giving instructions
当你使用指令调整型LLM时，请想象你在给另一个人下达指令，
to another person, say someone that's smart but doesn't know
比如说，聪明但不了解
the specifics of your task.
你任务具体内容的人。
So when an LLM doesn't work, sometimes it's because the instructions
所以，当LLM不起作用时，有时是因为指令
weren't clear enough.
不够清晰。
For example, if you were to say, "Please write me something
例如，如果你说：“请给我写点关于
about Alan Turing," well, in addition to that, it can be helpful to be clear
艾伦·图灵的事，"那么，除此之外，明确以下内容会有所帮助
about whether you want the text to focus on his scientific work
你希望文本聚焦于他的科学工作，
or his personal life or his role in history or something else.
还是他的个人生活、历史地位或是其他方面。
And if you specify what you want the tone of the text to be,
如果你明确了希望文本的语调，
should it take on the tone like a professional journalist would write,
是像专业记者那样的语调，
or is it more of a casual note that you dash off to a friend?
还是更像是给朋友随意写的便条？
That helps the LLM generate what you want.
这有助于LLM生成你想要的内容。
And of course, if you picture yourself asking, say,
当然，如果你设想问下自己，比如说，
a fresh college graduate to carry out this task for you,
（你让）一个刚毕业的大学生为你完成这个任务，
if you can even specify what snippets of text they should read
如果你能明确他们应该阅读哪些文本段落，
in advance to write this text about Alan Turing,
以便提前撰写关于艾伦·图灵的文字，
then that even better sets up that fresh college grad for success
那么这将更好地帮助那位刚毕业的大学生成功地
to carry out this task for you.
为你完成这个任务。
So in the next video, you see examples of how to be clear and specific,
下一个视频中，你将会看到如何清晰、明确地描述提示的示例，
which is an important principle of prompting LLMs,
这是LLM提示工程的一个重要原则，
and you also learn from Isa a second principle of prompting,
同时你还将从Isa那里学到提示工程的第二个重要原则，
that is giving the LLM time to think.
那就是给予LLM一些思考的时间。
So with that, let's go on to the next video.
那么现在，让我们继续观看下一个视频。